Register of the Ray Lyman Wilbur papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ray Lyman Wilbur papers
1906-1964
XX392
Hoover Institution Archives
143 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 6 envelopes, 4 photo albums, 3 framed photographs, 4 sound discs, memorabilia (70.1 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, memoranda, reports, pamphlets, other printed matter, and miscellanea relating to American and world politics, the administrations of Herbert Hoover and Franklin D. Roosevelt, development of natural resources in the United States, national health and other social problems, the Boy Scouts of America, and the death of President Warren G. Harding. Includes papers accumulated by R. L. Wilbur as a member and officer of the Institute of Pacific Relations relating to the study of political, social, and economic conditions in East Asia and of American foreign policy in East Asia.
Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949.
Kelley, Ralph S.
Access
Box 146 may not be used without permission of the Archivist. Remainder of collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1875 April 13 Born, Boonesboro, Iowa
1896-1897 Instructor, Physiology, Stanford University
1900-1903 Assistant Professor, Physiology, Stanford University
1909-1916 Professor of Medicine, Stanford University
1911-1916 Dean, Medical School, Stanford University
1912-1913 President, American Academy of Medicine
1916-1943 President, Stanford University
1917 Chief, Conservation Division, United States Food Administration
1917, 1941-1946 California State Council of Defense
1922-1924 Chairman, Survey of Race Relations on Pacific Coast
1922-1925 Council of Social and Health Agencies, San Francisco
1923-1924 President, American Medical Association
1925-1929 Chairman, Institute of Pacific Relations
1927-1939 San Francisco Community Chest
1928 United States delegate to the Sixth Pan-American Conference, Havana
1928-1929 California State Park Commission
1929-1931 Chairman, White House Conference on Child Health and Protection
1929-1933 Secretary, Department of the Interior Author, Annual Reports of the Secretary of the Interior Federal Oil Conservation Board
1930-1931 Chairman, National Advisory Commission on Illiteracy
1931 Author (with William Atherton DuPuy), Conservation
1933 Author (with Northcutt Ely), Hoover Dam Contracts Author (with Elwood Mead), Construction of Hoover Dam
1936 Author, Stanford Horizons
1937 Author (with Arthur M. Hyde), Hoover Policies
1938 Author, March of Medicine
1939-1949 National Executive Board, Boy Scouts of America
1940 Author, Human Hopes
1940-1949 Health Commission, Boys Clubs of America
1944-1946 California State War Problems Board
1949 June 26 Died, Stanford, California
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, memoranda, reports, pamphlets, other printed matter, and miscellanea relating to American and world politics, the administrations of Herbert Hoover and Franklin D. Roosevelt, development of natural resources in the United States, national health and other social problems, the Boy Scouts of America, and the death of President Warren G. Harding. Includes papers accumulated by R. L. Wilbur as a member and officer of the Institute of Pacific Relations relating to the study of political, social, and economic conditions in East Asia and of American foreign policy in East Asia.
Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Boy Scouts.; United States. Department of the Interior.; Institute of Pacific Relations.; Education--United States.; Hoover Dam (Ariz. and Nev.); Literacy--United States.; Indians of North America.; Japanese Americans.; National parks and reserves--United States.; Natural resources--United States.; Oil-shales--United States.; Pan-Pacific relations.; Prohibition--United States.; Public health--United States.; Social problems.; World politics.; China--Foreign relations.; East Asia--Economic conditions.; East Asia--Foreign relations--United States.; East Asia--Politics and government.; East Asia--Social conditions.; United States--Foreign relations--East Asia.; United States--Politics and government--1929-1933.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; United States--Social conditions.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Statesmen--United States.; Sound recordings.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1929-1949 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical sketch, obituary, clippings, and miscellany.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1917-1945 (Boxes 1-5)
  Drafts and printed copies of speeches and writings with related correspondence, arranged chronologically.
  - General
    Correspondence, including some short statements by Dr. Wilbur.
    - 1923 March - 1929 June (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - 1929 July-November (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - 1929 December - 1930 April (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - 1930 April-June (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - 1930 July - 1931 February (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - 1931 February-May (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - 1931 June-December (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 2: 2-3)
  - Undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Conference proceedings, 1917 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    Relates to higher education.
  - "Duty of Americans in the Present Crisis," typescript article, 1917 March (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - "Inescapable Responsibilities," typescript article, 1917 March (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - "Food and the War," speech transcript, 1917 December (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - "Fighting with Food," printed article, 1918 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - "War Problems and Food," printed letter to the editor, 1918 February (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - "Food Conservation for World Relief," printed speech transcript, 1918 November (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - "Russia, Our Neighbor," typescript, 1919 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - "Herbert Hoover--A Personal Sketch," mimeographed copy, 1920 (Box-folder 2: 13)
    See also: Box 146, Folder 5.
  - Miscellaneous writings on Herbert Hoover, 1920-1937 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    Includes: typed carbon double-spaced manuscript by R. L. Wilbur, "Herbert Hoover--the Beloved Chief," 11 pp. (10 pp. plus 1 p. outline), 4-to, N.P., undated, speech prepared for radio stations KPO (San Francisco) and KFI (Los Angeles), 1928 October 8
    Typed carbon double-spaced manuscript, "Herbert Hoover," 7 pp., 4-to, N.P., 1928 March 31
    Typed carbon news release, 2 pp., 4-to, N.P., By R. L. Wilbur, indicating how Herbert Hoover kept in close touch with the U.S., 1920 January 28
    Typed carbon manuscript, "Accomplishments of the Herbert Hoover Administration," 2 pp., 4-to, N.P., undated
    Typed carbon manuscript dictated by R. L. Wilbur, "On the Herbert Hoover Administration," 4 pp., 4-to, N.P., manuscript corrections by Herbert Hoover. Together with a 2 pp. pencil draft with corrections, 1937 March 15
    Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, New York, From Francis Snow to R. L. Wilbur, with printed proof sheets of article by Wilbur on Hoover, appearing in Current History, 1928 November 13
    Typed carbon manuscript, "Herbert Hoover from a Personal Standpoint," 16 pp. (14 pp.), 4-to, N.P., undated with manuscript corrections by R. L. Wilbur and one p. of additional notes
    Typed carbon manuscript of a speech, "Hoover The Beloved Chief," 9 pp. (10 pp.), 4-to. N.P., undated, by R. L. Wilbur and broadcast over stations KPO (San Francisco) and FKI (Los Angeles), 1928 October 8; and
    Typed carbon manuscript, "As I Know Herbert Hoover," 4 pp., 4-to, N.P., by R. L. Wilbur, 1931 December 4.
  - Conference proceedings, 1921 August (Box-folder 2: 15)
    Relates to public health.
  - "The University of the Future--A Recruiting and Training Center for the Public Health Professions," typescript speech transcript, 1922 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - "Universities Helping to Solve Industrial Problems of Industrial Relations," typescript, 1922 February (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Remarks, Association of American Universities conference, typescript, 1922 November (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Miscellaneous writings on medicine, 1923-1941 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Statement, clipping relating to the death of President Harding, 1923 August (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - "The Institute of Pacific Relations," typescript, 1925 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Speech, typescript, 1925 July (Box-folder 2: 22)
    Relates to the Institute of Pacific Relations.
  - "An Adventure in Friendship--The Story of the Institute of Pacific Relations," mimeographed copy, 1925 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - "Mutual Understanding in the Pacific," printed article, 1927 April (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - The Man of the Hour, printed pamphlet about Herbert Hoover published by the Republican National Committee, 1928 April (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - "The Havana Conference of 1928," typescripts, 1928 November (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - Miscellaneous writings, typescripts and letters, 1929 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Report, American Council on Medical Education, typescript, 1929 November (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Miscellaneous writings, typescripts and letters, 1930 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Speeches, primarily letters and typescripts, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    Relating to child health.
  - Miscellaneous writings, typescripts and letters, 1931 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - "Damming the Oil Flood," printed copy, 1931 February (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - "The Indian Today," typescript and printed copy, 1931 March (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - "The Rehabilitation of the Virgin Islands," typescript, 1931 March (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - "What the Children's Charter Means to the Nation," printed copy, 1931 April (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - "The Public Lands," typescript, 1931 April (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - "A Progress Report at the Department of the Interior," typescript and correspondence, 1931 May (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - "The Nation's Playgrounds," typescript and correspondence, 1931 May (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - "A New Day for the Indian," printed copy and correspondence, 1931 May (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - "The Treatment of the American Indian," typescript and letters, 1931 May (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Interview, printed copy, 1931 May (Box-folder 3: 15)
    Relates to the Virgin Islands.
  - "Irrigation: Miracle of the Arid West," printed copy, 1931 June (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - "Wilbur Diagnoses Oil Ailments," printed copy and letters, 1931 July (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - "Hoover Dam and Nevada," typescript and letters, 1931 September (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - "Secretary of Interior Tells of Arizona Visit," printed copy, 1931 October (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - "Illiteracy and the Campaign to Remove It," typescript, 1931 November (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - "The Meaning of the Boulder Canyon Project to the Southwest," typescript and letters, 1931 November (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - "End Intellectual Lock Step," printed copy and letters, 1931 December (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - "As I Know Herbert Hoover," typescript and correspondence, 1931 December (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - "The Moulding of Americans," typescript and letters, 1931 December (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Miscellaneous writings, typescripts, printed copies, and letters, 1932 (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - Miscellaneous writings, printed copies and typescripts, 1934-1941 (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - Hoover Policies (co-author with Arthur M. Hyde, 1937), acknowledgements from libraries for donated copies (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Hoover Policies (co-author with Arthur M. Hyde, 1937), acknowledgements, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 4: 1-5)
    Also includes other letters and reviews.
  - Hoover Policies (co-author with Arthur M. Hyde, 1937), acknowledgements, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
    Folder 2, titled "Hoover Policies (Book) 1928," includes 28 miscellaneous Ls and Ls of compliments to R. L. Wilbur for his book, Hoover Policies, various sizes, V. P., V. D., some with carbon typed replies; together with three newspaper clippings reviewing book (35 pieces and 6 newspaper clippings).
  - "International Expositions as Factors for Peace," typescript and letters, 1938 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - "A Philosophy of American Education," printed copy and letters, 1938 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - "Human Hopes," printed copy, 1939 June (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - "China Has Much to Offer," printed copy, 1940 January (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Radio broadcast, typescript and recording, 1940 January (Box-folder 5: 7)
    Relates to international relations. See also: SOUND RECORDINGS
  - "Statehood for Hawaii," printed copy, 1940 October (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - "What Kind of World Order Do We Want?," printed copy and recording of radio broadcast, 1940 November (Box-folder 5: 9)
    See also: SOUND RECORDINGS
  - "The Past Half Century and Medical Education," mimeographed copy, 1941 January (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Speeches relating to Pacific relations, typescripts, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - "Our Pacific Destiny," printed and mimeographed copies of speech transcript, 1941 June (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Lou Henry Hoover, printed copy of memorial tribute to Mrs. Hoover, 1944 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Radio statement, typescript, 1945 February (Box-folder 5: 14)
    Relates to the United Nations Conference in San Francisco.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1917-1949 (Boxes 5-10)
  Correspondence, arranged chronologically, includes printed and non-printed material relating to many of the issues in the other series, such as social and health organizations and international relations.
  - General, Stanford alumni and miscellaneous (Box-folder 5: 15-16)
  - General (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - 1917-1940
    - A-R (Box-folder 6: 2-5)
    - S-Z (Box-folder 7: 1)
      Includes ALs, 3 pp., 12-mo, U.S.S. Mayflower, from Joel T. Boone to R. L. Wilbur, 1923 November 22
      Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, Marion, Ohio, from Carl W. Sawyer to R. L. Wilbur, 1925 September 29; and
      Typed Ls, 3 pp., 4-to, Marion, Ohio, from Carl W. Sawyer to R. L. Wilbur, together with two reprinted copies of letters by C. E. Sawyer and C. W. Sawyer. C. E. Sawyer was President Harding's personal physician.
  - 1941-1949
    - General, miscellaneous (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - A-C (Box-folder 7: 3-5)
    - D-Z (Box-folder 8: 1-6)
  - Pease, Vera Jane, 1917-1945 (Box-folder 9: 1-4)
    Primarily from 1941-1945, but includes letters from World War I service in France.
  - Pease, Vera Jane (Box-folder 10: 1-6)
- BOY SCOUTS OF AMERICA FILE, 1922-1949 (Boxes 11-18)
  Letters, reports, minutes, clippings, and financial materials, arranged chronologically.
  - General, 1922-1946 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
    Books and information on other boys' organizations.
  - 1930 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - 1930 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - 1931-1934 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 12: 3-4)
  - 1939 (Box-folder 13: 1-3)
  - 1940 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - 1940 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
  - 1941 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - 1941 (Box-folder 15: 1-3)
  - 1942 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - 1942 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - 1943 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - 1943 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - 1944 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - 1945 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - 1946 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - 1947 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - 1948 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - 1949 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- HERBERT HOOVER FILE, 1916-1964 (Boxes 19-21)
  Correspondence with Herbert Hoover and others, pamphlets, reports, speech transcripts, and miscellany relating to the death of President Warren Harding, the administration of President Herbert Hoover, the President's Commission on Home Building and Home Ownership, and other subjects, arranged by form.
  - General
    - Harding, Warren G., 1923
      Material relating to President Harding's death at which both Mr. Hoover and Dr. Wilbur were present. Items listed below are not necessarily in the folders in the order in which they appear below.
      - Typed notes copying telegram from Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1 p., 4-to, Dunsmuir, California, 1923 July 28 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - ALs, 2 pp., oblong 8-vo, San Francisco, from Dr. Charles M. Cooper to R. L. Wilbur, undated
        Together with attached typed carbon N from Dr. Cooper to General Sawyer.
      - Typed telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, Chicago, 1923 August 8
      - Manuscript notes, 4-pp., 8-vo, N.P., on Palace Hotel stationery, San Francisco, undated
        Notes by R. L. Wilbur on Harding's condition, together with a typed carbon page re Harding's condition.
      - ALs, 2-pp., 4-to, San Francisco, from Dr. Charles M. Cooper to R. L. Wilbur, 1923 August 13
      - Miscellaneous typed telegrams, Ls, typed carbon L between Charles E. Sawyer and R. L. Wilbur, 11 pieces, various sizes, V. P., V. D.
      - Telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, Dunsmuir, California, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1923 July 28
        Together with manuscript version of the telegram.
      - Two typed copies of N, 1 p. each, 4-to, N.P., from Florence K. Harding to R. L. Wilbur, 1923 August 28
      - Four miscellaneous typed carbon N, 4 pp., various sizes, V. P., V. D. from R. L. Wilbur to C. Clemens
        Together with a card signed by Clemens.
      - ALs, 2 pp., 8-vo, East Northfield, Massachusetts, from "Theresa" to R. L. Wilbur
      - Two typed carbon copies of telegram, oblong 8-vo, San Francisco, from R. L. Wilbur to San Francisco Examiner, together with 2 pp., manuscript and bill, 1923 August 3
      - Miscellaneous correspondence re Harding's death, from Paul Shoup, Curtis Weber (Wilbur), Donald Smith, the Misses Tomkins, et. al.
      - Manuscript note relating to details of Harding's condition, 1 p., 16-mo, N.P., on Stanford University Hospital stationery, undated
      - Miscellaneous clipped together correspondence between R. L. Bentley and R. L. Wilbur, relating to the possibility of food poisoning by canned goods in Harding's death
      - Typed manuscript, "Personal Memorandum of Attendance on President Harding During His Illness, July and August 1923," 11 pp. (12 pp.), 4-to, N.P., 1923 August (Box-folder 19: 2)
        Written by R. L. Wilbur and signed on first p. and with manuscript notes. Together with two AN regarding press contacts by R. L. Wilbur about the Harding illness.
      - Typed Ls, 2 pp., 4-to, New York, from Dr. Liebman to R. L. Wilbur, 1940 January 9
        Together with typed carbon reply, January 13, 1940.
      - Typed carbon for R. L. Wilbur, part titled "Warren G. Harding," 2 pp., 4-to, N.P., undated
        From a Wilbur manuscript sent to C. Clemens for the latter's biography of Harding.
      - Pencil manuscript of R. L. Wilbur, "The Last Illness of a Calm Man," 21 pp., 4-to, N.P., undated
        With notation copy sent to Saturday Evening Post and The New York Times, August 12, 1923.
      - Typed carbon manuscript by R. L. Wilbur and C. M. Cooper, "President Harding's Last Illness, Official Bulletins," 3 pp., 4-to, N.P., from the Journal of the American Medical Association, Vol. LXXXI, No. 7, p. 603, 1923 August 18
      - Typed notes for R. L. Wilbur autobiography, 3 pp., 4-to, N.P., dictated, 1944 March 7
      - Four miscellaneous printed articles (7 pieces) related to Harding's death and one copy of Collier's, 1923 August 4
      - 12 miscellaneous pieces (37 pieces) all related to Harding's death. Discussions, correspondence, galley, proofs, articles, etc.
      - Harding clippings (Box-folder 19: 3)
        Folder containing mounted newspaper clippings from the U.S. press re President Harding's illness and death and events related to his death.
    - President's Commission on Home Building and Home Ownership. Ray Lyman Wilbur, President, Better Homes in America, Inc.
      - Correspondence, 1929-1938
        - General, 1933-1946 (Box-folder 19: 4)
        - Architectural Forum (Box-folder 19: 5-6)
        - Books/publishing, 1935-1941 (Box-folder 19: 7)
      - Administrative and personnel material (Box-folder 19: 8)
      - Printed material, 1916-1941 (Box-folder 19: 9-10)
      - Financial material, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 19: 11)
        Primarily correspondence involving Edgar Rickard and Raymond H. Sawtelle.
      - Financial material, 1930-1938 (Box-folder 20: 1-8)
    - Stanford University, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 20: 9)
      Relates to contributions for building projects. 31 miscellaneous typed Ls (30 only), carbons, etc., 4-to, V. P., relating to sums of money given by the office of Edgar Rickard (of Hoover's New York office) to Stanford University.
  - Correspondence
    - General, Dr. Wilbur with others, 1917-1946 (Box-folder 20: 10-11)
    - Beard, Charles A., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 20: 12)
      Miscellaneous letters, drafts, carbons between Charles Beard and R. L. Wilbur regarding the former's book, Basic History, which accounts for Herbert Hoover's place in history. 21 pieces (22 pieces Beard to Wilbur plus 3 notes Beard to Wilbur), various sizes, V. P., August 30, 1944 to November 9, 1945. Together with 12 pp. tearsheet of article by Beard, "Thomas Jefferson, a Civilized Man," Miss. Valley Historical Review, with penned dedication by Beard to Wilbur. Together with two typed Ns, 2 pp., 8-vo, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur.
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1912-1948
      - 1912-1928 (Box-folder 21: 1)
        - ALs, 4 pp., 12-mo, Melrose, Oakland, California, from Lou Henry Hoover (Mrs. Hoover) to R. L. Wilbur, 1912
        - Seven miscellaneous telegrams, various sizes and places, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1915-1923
          Includes one 1915 telegram from Lou Henry Hoover.
        - Typed Ls, 3 pp., 4-to, London, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1916 November 22
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, together with a typed carbon draft of a press release, 4 pp., 1920 April 15
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1920 June 4
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, New York, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1921 January 21
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1921 July 27
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1921 December 2
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1922 July 28
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1923 April 6
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 8-vo, Stanford, from Mrs. Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1923 September 24
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1925 April 18
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1925 June 6
        - Typed Ls, 2 pp., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1926 February 4
        - Typed carbon of a telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, Stanford, from R. L. Wilbur to Herbert Hoover, 1926 February 11
        - Typed Ls, 2 pp., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1926 February 13
        - Typed Ls, 1 p., 4-to, N.P., Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1926 April 20
        - Typed telegram, 1 p., oblong 8-vo, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1926 July 10
        - Typed carbon N, 1 p., 4-to, Washington, Asst. Secretary to Mr. Henry A. Pfister re Herbert Hoover's registration in California, 1926 July 19
        - Typed Ns, 1 p., 4-to, Washington, from Herbert Hoover to R. L. Wilbur, 1926 October 12